Christina Boat 515.419.2983 Boat.Christina@yahoo.com Des Moines, IA 50311

#### **PROFILE**

Motivated, personable business professional with experience and a successful track record

of maintaining excellent customer service satisfaction. Talent for quickly mastering tasks given to complete.

Diplomatic and tactful with professional and non-professionals at all levels. Accustomed to handling sensitive, confidential records. *F lexible and versatile*- able to maintain a sense of humor under pressure. Poised and competent with demonstrated ability to easily tr anscend differences. Thrive in deadline-driven environments. Excellent team-building skills.

# **Community Based Case Manager**

### Anthem, West Des Moines, IA – Present

Highly-dedicated, organized, and compassionate Case Manager with experience in quality health-care to members. Solid understanding of working with members from various illnesses to ensure personal healthcare goals are accomplished.

- Takes lead role in helping with training material and presentation for co-workers.
- Involved in Anthem's leadership program HYPE (Healthcare Your Professional Exchange)
- Strong experience of social skills, and coordinating health care services for members.
- Ability to interact with medical teams/programs at all levels.
- Experienced in scheduling and coordinating care plan meetings, admission meetings and treatment plans for members.
- Experience in scheduling and coordinating meetings strategically and cost effective.
- Possess exceptional leadership and communication skills.
- Collaborating with doctors, physicians, nurses, caregivers, and providers for arranging clinical resources and medical care for members.
- Conducting detailed assessments of member's personal health goals and care plans.
- Froviding psychological and emotional support resources to members as well as their families dealing with chronic or acute illnesses
- Arrange for transportation service for pick up and drop off for members.
- Initiating home meal delivery and transportation for follow-up appointments to provide long-term care solutions
- **Examining** and discussing funding issues with patients and family members.

### **Medical Management Specialist**

#### Anthem, West Des Moines, IA - 2017-2018

- Assisting Case Managers in authorizing services members need to obtain personal health goals.
- An exceptional resource for case managers to help complete unanswered questions regarding member's health care.
- Researched billing inquiries and denials for reprocessing.
- Built member cases in company data base (FACETS).
- Approved authorizations in FACETS for services. Sending letters of decision to providers supplying member's services.
- Verified provider licensure, TIN, and NPI.
- Ensured privacy of members protected health information.
- Lead and assisted various projects in a time sensitive environment for audit and reporting purposes to the state using various programs.

#### **Assistant Manager**

#### Tradehome Shoes, Fort Dodge, IA — 2016-2017

- Assistant manager to store manager.
- Trained 7-8 sales associated to sell products within the store.
- Interviewed/hired new employees.
- Wrote weekly schedule.
- Helped maintain 30% store gains, monthly, through personal sales.

- Helped build clientele from prior store loss.
- Demonstrated excellent customer service.

#### **Sales Associate**

## General Nutrition Company (GNC), Fort Dodge, IA - 2016-2017

- Lead sales associate.
- Educated customers on store products to help maintain a good healthy regimen.
- Lead team in new accounts while helping to maintain and exceed store goals.
- Maintained daily balanced cash register.
- Demonstrated excellent customer service.

### **Grievance & Appeals Liaison**

#### Anthem, West Des Moines, IA - 2015-2016

- Answered calls from members regarding their concerns regarding local physicians.
- Answered calls from members regarding an appeal with a current decision regarding denial of their benefit.
- Researched members' benefits for a customer satisfactory decision.
- Conduct executive decisions for problem solving issues.
- ≤ Acted as liaison between member and professional and non-professional peers for best resolution of member's concern.
- Stated cases needing medical review from the nurses on our team.
- Obtained critical incident information for reporting purposes to the state.

## **Employment History**

-Post Issue Customer Service

-High Touch (death claims)

MetLife, West Des Moines, IA − 2013-2015

Locum Tenans Credentialer

Acute Care Inc., Ankeny, IA - 2009-2010

### **Education**

Bachelor of Arts in Management, Concentration in Logistics & Operations *Southern New Hampshire University- Current*Associate of Applied Science for Medical Assisting *Kaplan University, Urbandale, IA — 2004-2005*Medical Transcription Certificate *Kaplan University, Urbandale, IA- 2004-2005*